Seigo Saeki…
佐伯清剛
Ichiro… Tokai?
渡海一郎？
Because I don't trust that man.
因為我不相信那個人
That man…
那個人
betrayed my father.
背叛了我爸爸
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
Nurse.
護理長
We're done here. Please go check on the pharmaceuticals.
這邊可以了，你回去檢查藥品
-But… -I'll take care of the rest.
-可是… -剩下的我來就好
Okay, I understand.
好，我知道了
Soon after,
不久之後
an event took place that shook Tojo to its core.
發生了一件震驚東城大學的大事
Welcome to Teika University.
歡迎來到帝華大學
Thank you.
謝謝
It happened after the surgery of Dr. Tokai's mother was complete.
事情發生在渡海夫人的手術結束之後
At Tojo University,
在東城大學
doctors performing surgery on family members
醫生為家屬動手術這件事
is strictly prohibited.
是嚴格禁止的
As punishment, a third of your pay will be cut.
作為處分，你被減薪三分之一
That is my final decision.
這是我的最終決定
One-third?
三分之一？
If you have something to say, speak up.
如果你有意見就說吧
There is one thing I want to check.
我倒是想知道一件事
I've received an offer from Teika University…
帝華大學邀請我去任職
for the double of what you're paying me.
他們說要給我雙倍的薪水
Teika University?
帝華大學？
You're cutting my already low pay.
薪水原本就低了，還被扣錢
I have a life to live.
我也是要過生活的
Professor?
教授？
It's up to Dr. Tokai.
渡海自己決定
Thank you for everything.
謝謝您一直以來的照顧
RESIGNATION LETTER
（辭呈）
BY REQUEST, THE PERSON LISTED BELOW WILL RESIGN
（下述人員將於今日自願離職）
Throwing it all away for money?
為了錢拋棄這一切啊？
And going to Teika University, of all places?
而且還偏偏是去帝華大學？
Doesn't he have any morals as a doctor?
他難道沒有身為醫生的原則可言嗎？
Seriously.
就是說啊
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Take care of that for me. I don't need this either.
幫我收拾那邊，我也不要這個了
Dr. Tokai left Tojo University
渡海醫生離開了東城大學
as if he were never here in the first place.
彷彿他根本從沒來過的樣子
It would appear that the man is obsessed with money, just like you said.
跟你說的一樣，他是個見錢眼開的人
He didn't bat an eye ditching Tojo to join me here.
眼睛都不眨一下 就立刻來我們這裡了
What do you plan to do with him?
您打算要他做什麼？
You focus on your own job.
你做好自己的事情就好
Got it…
聽到了沒？
Dr. Takashina?
高階？
Taking a nap already? He just got here.
已經在睡午覺了？他才剛來耶
Why did Dr. Nishizaki bring him here?
西崎教授為什麼要找他來？
Beats me.
我不知道
Anyway, we've been ordered not to let him do anything until after the election.
總之教授說，理事長選舉結束前 別派他做任何工作
At the same time, Mr. Tomizawa from the Ministry of Health
與此同時，厚勞省的富澤先生
came to Tojo to promote the Japan-made Darwin, Caesar.
來到東城大學 推廣國產的達爾文機器人凱撒
Rumor has it, Dr. Saeki,
佐伯教授，我聽說
that you deliberately choose the most difficult cases.
凱撒研究的病例 您都特地挑選最難的
That's not my intention.
我並沒有刻意這樣做
I would like you to focus on lower-risk patients from now on.
希望您今後可以選擇風險較低的患者
I need you to perform surgeries with a high success rate.
積極做一些絕對會成功的手術
On that note,
說到這個
I've heard that a patient named Shoko Yamamoto
我聽說有位名叫山本祥子的患者
is currently being admitted.
正在你們這裡住院
AORTIC VALVE INSUFFICIENCY
（主動脈瓣關閉不全）
Yes, we have indeed admitted Shoko Yamamoto.
我們的確有位名叫山本祥子的患者
She may be the perfect case for the Caesar.
可以說是非常適合凱撒的病例
This is Dr. Nishizaki's doing, I'm sure.
這一定是西崎教授安排的吧
To speed up the clinical trials,
為了加速試驗
he has talked to Mr. Tomizawa from the Ministry of Health.
請厚勞省的富澤先生過來幫忙說話
But how did he get our patient's information?
但他怎麼有我們醫院的患者資訊？
Someone told Dr. Nishizaki.
有人告訴西崎教授的吧？
There is no other explanation.
沒有別的可能了
I'm sure that Shoko Yamamoto
我記得山本祥子
was Dr. Tokai's patient.
是渡海醫生負責的
So Dr. Tokai did it?
是渡海說的嗎？
When he was recruited by Teika University,
他被帝華大學聘去的時候
perhaps he took our data as a parting gift.
大概拿我們醫院的資料當見面禮了吧
Whatever the case, we must hurry.
不管怎樣，我們都得加快速度
Mr. Tomizawa's request is, in effect, the request of the entire nation.
富澤先生的要求就是國家的要求
-That's right. -If that's so,
-是 -如果是這樣
I insist that you leave this one to me, doctor.
請您將這次的手術交給我
This is a low-risk patient, it doesn't matter who's in charge.
這種低風險的病例 誰來負責都不會失敗
Make this a win for Tojo.
一定要為東城立功
Thank you.
謝謝教授
What is this about? I'm supposed to be overseeing the Caesar.
這是怎麼回事？凱撒應該由我負責
You put the patient in danger during the last clinical trial.
你在上次試驗手術中將病患置於險地
We didn't have enough blood transfusion.
那是因為血袋不夠
This is the professor's order.
這是教授的命令
You'll assist me.
你可以協助
Yes, sir.
是
Dr. Saeki.
佐伯醫生
Oh. Sorry to call you so suddenly. We would like to continue the trial.
抱歉突然叫你來 我們想進行下一場試驗
I would be happy to cooperate.
我很樂意幫忙
-You take care of the rest. -Yes.
-剩下的交給你 -是
Shoko Yamamoto.
山本祥子小姐
She worked as a nurse at a nearby hospital.
在附近的醫院擔任護理師主任
…that will make it easier to locate the veins.
這樣血管突起來，能夠更容易找到
Wow, you're right.
真的耶
-Drawing blood is about speed and courage. -I see.
-抽血就是要有速度跟膽量 -是
Pardon me.
打擾了
I've called in the clinical trial coordinator I told you about.
我剛才跟您說的臨床試驗協調員來了
I'll introduce her now.
我來介紹一下
Pardon me. My name is Kinoshita…
打擾了，我是木下…
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
Pardon me.
不好意思
Hey. What was that about?
喂，剛才那是怎麼回事？
Hey!
喂！
What about the explanation?
試驗的說明呢？
Did something happen between you and Ms. Kinoshita?
您和木下小姐之間發生過什麼事嗎？
Kaori and I used to work at the same hospital.
香織和我曾在同一家醫院工作過
-Here. -Thank you.
-拜託了 -謝謝
During an operation,
有一次手術中
Kaori was a scrub nurse, passing equipment.
香織負責遞手術用具
-Fix the circulation, hurry! -Right.
-處理循環問題，快點！ -是
-But… -Get the heart-lung machine.
-可是… -準備人工心肺機
-The heart has stopped. -Administer bosmin. We'll need more blood.
-心跳停止了 -注射腎上腺素，需要更多血袋
Why did you give the removal tool?
為什麼拿排血管給我？
We needed to pump in blood! This is your fault!
應該拿輸血管的，都是你的錯！
She claimed her innocence,
她說自己是無辜的
but the surgeon refused to admit his own mistake
但醫生拒絕承認是他自己的過失
and shifted the blame solely on Kaori.
把責任全部推給香織
As for me,
至於我
I was threatened to be fired if I didn't tell my side of the story.
也被威脅如果不做偽證 就會遭到開除
Operating nurse Ms. Kinoshita
手術室護理師木下小姐
mistakenly handed the doctor the wrong tool.
遞器具給醫生時拿錯了
She was made fully responsible for the mistake
她被迫承擔全部的責任
and was let go by the hospital.
並且被醫院開除
Even though she was a wonderful nurse.
她是一位很優秀的護理師
But there was no one who would protect her.
可是卻沒有一個人站出來保護她
A person's greatest enemy is other people.
人最大的敵人，就是人
I would greatly consider the clinical trial,
試驗的部分，我會好好考慮一下
but could you put someone else in charge?
不過能不能請別的協調員過來？
I heard what happened.
我聽說發生什麼事了
So you were a nurse.
原來你以前是護理師啊
At that time,
當時
I even wished she would die.
我甚至希望她去死
Do as she wishes. Put someone else on the job.
就照她的要求，換一個協調員吧
I didn't know she had a history like that.
我都不知道她有那樣的過去
Ms. Kinoshita and Dr. Tokai were pretty close.
木下小姐和渡海醫生的關係很好吧
Maybe we can ask him about it.
或許可以跟他談一談
But he's not here anymore.
但他不在這裡了
-This will be a pain to clean up. -Jeez.
-這裡收拾起來真是痛苦 -哎呀
Dr. Nishizaki, new data will be arriving shortly.
西崎教授，新的數據就快到了
We'll be verifying it here, yes.
我們會在這裡確認，是
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
How are you finding Teika University?
帝華大學怎麼樣啊？
Who are you?
你是哪位？
My name is Takeda.
我是武田
Don't you remember me?
你不記得我了？
Try not to get too lost here.
盡量不要在這裡迷路了
What do you mean by "I need rest"?
“需要休息”是什麼意思？
You can't just take three weeks off like that.
你不能就這樣休息三週
-I need a break. -What is it?
-我需要休息 -怎麼了？
Without Dr. Tokai here, Nekota doesn't want to work.
渡海醫生不在，貓田就不想做事了
Do your job.
做好你份內的工作
That is an order.
這是命令
Truly appalling, nurses these days.
現在的護理師真是太誇張了
If you won't follow orders,
你不聽從命令的話
you can leave just like Dr. Tokai.
可以跟渡海醫生一樣離開
Director, I will take care of this. I assure you.
院長，我跟您保證我會好好處理
Isn't that right, Nekota?
可以吧，貓田護理師？
I can't believe it. I'm counting on you, head nurse.
真不敢相信，護理長，就拜託你了
Don't you think director Moriya has been really on edge lately.
你不覺得守屋院長 最近經常發脾氣嗎？
Running around between Dr. Saeki and the Ministry of Health…
畢竟被夾在佐伯醫生和厚勞省之間…
Of course he's venting.
他當然會發脾氣啊
You can't blame him.
這也不能怪他
If you can't follow orders, it's game over.
不聽從指示就完蛋了
So you're telling me that Dr. Saeki
所以你的意思是佐伯教授
has been choosing high-risk patients for clinical trials?
故意選擇風險較高的患者做試驗嗎？
That's right.
沒錯
After the newest medical tools were used,
用最新的醫療器材動完手術後
he made sure to finish things with his scalpel.
他還是得用手術刀收尾的那種手術
In other words,
換句話說
trying to prove the ability of a surgeon's skill over new technology.
就是想證明 外科醫生的技術還是比較重要
The patient's safety must be made a top priority in clinical trials.
試驗的病例應該將患者的安全擺優先
You don't need to worry.
你不必擔心
This time, we are backed by Mr. Tomizawa from the Ministry of Health.
我們這次得到了 厚勞省富澤先生的支持
We've chosen a low-risk patient.
選擇了手術風險低的患者
There will be no failure.
不會失敗
You've "chosen"?
“選擇了”？
Are you saying you have possession of Tojo's patient data?
你是說你有東城大學患者的資訊嗎？
Well,
這個嘛
we have a few people on our side.
有一些人在幫我
We've picked a doctor that Dr. Saeki has been training in the shadows.
我們找來了一位 默默支持佐伯教授的醫生
Thanks to this new development,
有這樣的新發展
Tojo will no longer be able to handle difficult operations successfully.
東城大學再也不能 成功進行困難的手術了
In two days, you'll undergo surgery for mitral valve insufficiency.
兩天後要進行 二尖瓣閉鎖不全症的手術
All right. Excuse me, doctor?
好，不好意思，醫生？
I'll see you tomorrow.
那明天見
Yes? Dr. Nishizaki. Just a moment.
喂？西崎教授，請等一下
-My neck has been killing me lately. -Really?
-我的脖子最近痛得要死 -是嗎？
-I can't really move it. -Is that so?
-我都動不了 -這樣啊
I must have slept the wrong way.
我可能是落枕了
It seems like something happened in the past
渡海醫生的父親和佐伯教授之間
between Dr. Tokai's dad and Dr. Saeki.
好像發生過什麼
What?
什麼？
I overheard something recently.
我最近偶然聽到的
Because I don't trust that man.
因為我不信任那個人
That man betrayed my father.
那個人背叛了我爸爸
-Betrayed? -Yes.
-背叛？ -對
That reminds me.
我想起來了
When I was transporting those documents, I came across an old paper.
我在搬資料時，看到了一本舊論文
A paper?
論文？
Yes.
對
The authors were Dr. Saeki and Ichiro Tokai.
作者是佐伯醫生和渡海一郎
So the betrayal must have been…
那麼背叛一定就是…
There was one thing left over from the documents we transported.
從事務樓搬過來的資料中 只剩下這一本
This brings me back.
真是懷念
I learned so much from Dr. Ichiro Tokai.
我從渡海一郎醫生那裡學到了好多
"A university hospital is established on practical skills and research."
“大學附屬醫院 建立在實踐技能和研究之上”
That's what he told me.
這是他告訴我的
He sure put my arrogant self in my place.
他還會挫挫我的銳氣 讓我別那麼自大
But I threw all of that away.
不過我把那些都拋在腦後了
PLEASE INSERT ID CARD
（請插入證件）
-What are you doing? -This computer doesn't work.
-你在做什麼？ -電腦壞了
-You need an ID card. -Give me yours.
-要插入證件才行 -你的給我
What?
什麼？
I'm sorry, I can't. There is important data on there.
抱歉，不行，裡面有機密資料
I can't allow you to touch it.
我不准你動
Why, are you thinking of writing a paper?
怎樣，你想寫論文？
A paper?
論文？
It looks like this super doctor from Tojo University
看來東城大學來的這位超級醫生
has never written a paper before.
從沒寫過論文呢
Online shopping.
我是要網路購物
What?
什麼？
Your hospital doesn't have a rice cooker.
這間醫院裡沒有炊飯器
A rice cooker?
炊飯器？
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Don't mess with that!
不要亂碰！
I'm making sure the arm movement has improved.
我要確保機械手臂的移動有所改良
I'll do it.
我會自己來
If you screw up this top-secret data too, we'll be in trouble.
你要是動到這裡的機密數據 那可就糟了
Are you suggesting I would steal our patients' data?
你是想說，我偷了病患資料嗎？
I didn't say that.
我沒這麼說
How is it going with the new clinical trial coordinator?
話說，找到新的試驗協調員了嗎？
As a member of Tojo University Hospital,
身為東城大學的一員
I need you to stay on your toes.
你可要隨時做好準備才行
One tiger prawn.
一份明蝦
It seems like we've found a replacement coordinator.
聽說我們找到了其他的協調員
The patient wasn't pleased with my presence.
因為患者對我不滿
Life is full of unexpected things.
人生就是充滿各種意料之外的事情
Did you know about it?
你之前就知道了嗎？
About my malpractice.
我醫療過失那件事
If so, why did you continue to trust me all this time?
既然知道，為什麼還這麼信任我？
I'm a trial coordinator who caused a medical error.
我可是犯過醫療過失的協調員
If word were to get out, Tojo risks losing its credibility.
如果傳出去，東城大學會失去可信度
No matter what happened in the past, I trust what I see in front of me.
不管過去發生過什麼 我只相信我眼前看到的
You're an excellent person.
你是個很優秀的人
That's why I keep you around.
所以我才聘用你
The past is what you make of it.
所謂的過去 都是人們自己編撰出來的東西
The truth.
事情的真相
True pain.
真正的痛苦
It's not for others to understand.
只有當事人自己清楚
-How's the Caesar operating? -We're preparing meticulously.
-凱撒的效能如何？ -我們正在認真準備中
-I'm counting on you. -Right.
-我就靠你了 -是
Please pass the ethics committee documents to Dr. Takashina.
請將道德委員會的文件交給高階醫生
-Understood. -Also…
-知道了 -還有…
Make sure Ms. Yamamoto is administered heparin and penicillin.
替山本小姐注射肝素和盤尼西林
-Right. -Okay.
-是
But before, Dr. Tokai didn't order a dose of penicillin.
可是之前負責的渡海醫生 都沒吩咐注射盤尼西林
It's Dr. Kurosaki's orders.
這是黑崎醫生的指示
Let's get it over with. I'll go see Ms. Yamamoto.
快點做就是了，我負責山本小姐那邊
-You give the documents to Dr. Takashina. -Okay.
-你把文件交給高階醫生 -好
Excuse me.
抱歉
PENICILLIN
（盤尼西林）
-It seems the next trial has been decided. -Yes.
-看來下一場試驗手術已經決定了 -是啊
-I'll have you assist as well. -Me?
-請你一起來協助吧 -我？
That patient was being checked by Dr. Tokai,
患者之前的醫生是渡海
which means she's your patient too.
也等於是你的病患
I've told Dr. Kurosaki.
我跟黑崎醫生說了
But, I'm only a…
但我只是個…
During that last surgery,
上一場手術
you were able to follow Dr. Tokai's orders instantly.
你立刻就能照渡海醫生的命令做事
After seeing your performance,
看過你的表現後
I've decided I need you for this.
我認為這台手術缺你不可
Thank you.
謝謝您的肯定
Dr. Takashina. The ethics committee documents.
高階醫生，這是道德委員會的文件
Thanks.
謝謝
Did Ms. Yamamoto get her medicine?
替山本小姐打點滴了嗎？
Miyamoto is giving her heparin and penicillin now.
宮元護理師拿肝素和盤尼西林過去了
What?
什麼？
-Penicillin? -Yes. Dr. Kurosaki's orders.
-盤尼西林？ -對，黑崎醫生的指示
That's not good. Ms. Yamamoto is allergic to penicillin.
不行啊，山本小姐對盤尼西林過敏
-Dr. Sera. -Right!
-世良 -是
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
Ms. Yamamoto, are you okay?
山本小姐，你還好嗎？
PENICILLIN
（盤尼西林）
Thank God.
謝天謝地
Excuse me.
不好意思
-Forgive us! -We're truly sorry.
-請原諒我們 -我們真的很抱歉
-The truth is… -I can't believe it.
-事實上… -真不敢相信
I never thought she would come to help me.
沒想到她會來幫我
-She's allergic? -You put the patient in danger.
-過敏？ -你差點害患者陷入生命危險
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
Dr. Kurosaki would never do that!
黑崎醫生不可能會做那種事
He never gave you those orders.
他從沒有給那樣的指示
You must have misheard what he said.
你們一定是聽錯了
-But… -I'm very sorry.
-可是… -我很抱歉
Unbelievable.
真是的
If you can't do your job right,
如果工作做不好
you might as well just quit.
不如辭職算了
There are countless others who could replace you.
能取代你的人到處都是
Dr. Kurosaki. There's an important clinical trial coming up.
黑崎醫生，重要的試驗就快開始了
-Yes. -Well then. Dismissed!
-是 -那好吧，解散
-Why? -Why what?
-為什麼？ -沒有為什麼
Nothing happened. Let it go.
反正什麼事都沒發生，算了吧
After that,
在那之後
a new clinical trial coordinator was introduced.
來了一位新的臨床試驗協調員
This is our new coordinator, Mr. Yamauchi.
這位是新的臨床試驗協調員山內先生
It's a pleasure to meet you. I'm Dr. Yamauchi.
幸會，我是山內
I'll be coordinating the medical trial.
我會負責這次臨床試驗的協調工作
Actually, can I have Kaori do it after all?
能不能請香織回來呢？
I would like her to be in charge.
我想讓她負責
She did?
是嗎？
She said that if it's not you,
她說如果不是你負責
she doesn't intend to participate in the trial.
她就不參加這次試驗了
You're the only one who can do it. You wouldn't say no, would you?
只有你能辦到了，你不會拒絕吧？
Yes.
是
Yes, right. Okay.
是，好的
How are you finding Teika University?
你覺得帝華大學怎樣？
-What? -I have a little something for you.
-什麼？ -我帶了東西來給你
It's from Tokyo's oldest onigiri shop.
這是從東京最老的飯糰店買的
That's thoughtful of you. I left all my rice back at Tojo too.
你真貼心，我把米全部留在東城了
You're being treated as a thief back at Tojo.
東城大學那邊可是把你當成小偷了
-What? -The patients' data.
-什麼？ -患者資訊
It seems you've given it to Dr. Nishizaki.
好像洩漏到西崎教授那裡去了
So, are you here to get a checkup or something?
那你今天是來做檢查之類的嗎？
I'm here on business.
我是來工作的
I do work for Teika too, you know.
我也替帝華服務，你知道吧
You look like you should be a patient.
你的臉色看起來像個病人
This can't be good.
這下糟了
It's Dr. Takeda's operation.
是武田醫生的手術
What happened?
怎麼了？
-Blood pressure falling. -Bring transfusion.
-血壓降低 -快輸血
I guess food will have to wait.
飯糰得等一下了
Hurry up!
快點！
-VF persisting. -Damn it.
-室顫持續中 -可惡
VF won't stabilize.
室顫穩定不下來
What should we do?
怎麼辦？
The patient will die if we continue.
再這樣下去，患者會死的
-We must stop operating. -But…
-必須停止手術 -可是…
We're finished! Turn off the camera now.
結束了，關掉攝影機
Right.
是
What are you doing here? You've got no business here. Get out!
你來幹嘛？這裡沒你的事，出去！
The patient had a heart attack.
果然心肌梗塞了
How did you…
你怎麼知道？
He said his neck hurt, didn't he?
他說他脖子痛，不是嗎？
If you had checked the coronary artery, you would have known.
你當初如果檢查了冠狀動脈就會知道
How do you plan on fixing it?
所以，你打算怎麼解決？
Isn't it written in your little paper?
你那些小論文裡沒有寫嗎？
What are you doing? Turn the camera off!
你在做什麼？快關攝影機
Don't. If you turn it off, you're dead.
不要關，敢關掉我就殺了你
You were about to end the operation and be done with it, weren't you?
你剛剛打算結束手術 就這樣算了，不是嗎？
To make his death seem like it happened after the surgery?
打算偽裝成是患者在術後不幸死亡？
What's that?
什麼啊？
What is Teika researching, a cover-up?
原來帝華大學研究的 是如何隱瞞過失嗎？
Someone get this man out of here!
快把他趕出去！
If you have time to complain, hurry and save the patient.
要是你這麼有空，就快點救病人啊
It's too late for that.
已經太遲了
Ten million yen.
一千萬
Write your resignation letter.
寫辭呈吧
Pay me your severance money and I'll cover it up.
退職金一千萬給我，我就幫你解決
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼？
-VF persisting. -We don't have time!
-室顫還在持續 -來不及了！
Got it. I'll go tell your big boss then.
知道了 那我要去找你那位偉大的上司告狀了
Okay, fine.
好，我知道了
Help me.
幫幫我
Out of my way.
礙事
-We'll remove the inner artery. -Thoracotomy tool.
取出內胸動脈，開胸器
-Thoracotomy tool! -Right.
-開胸器！ -是
-Help me. -Okay.
-來幫我 -好
-Chair. -Right.
-椅子 -是
Electroscalpel.
電燒刀
Prepare the following things for me.
幫我準備接下來的東西
Stabilizer, CO2 blower, holder, beaver knife,
穩定器、二氧化碳充氣系統 固定器、海狸手術刀
micro scissors, microneedle holder, and 8-0.
微型剪、微型持針器和8-0號線
-Move it! -Yes.
-快點！ -是
-You remove the saphenous vein. -Okay!
-你取出大隱靜脈
Internal mammary artery dissected.
內胸動脈剝離處理完畢
He's fast.
好快
All done.
完成
Hurry up, will you?
快一點可以嗎？
-I'll take over. Move it. -Right.
-我來，走開 -是
What an incredible skill.
好厲害的技術
So this is Tojo University's devil of the operating room.
他就是東城大學手術室裡的惡魔啊
Get me the Metz.
準備組織剪
Metz.
組織剪給我
Okay. Suture complete.
好，縫合完畢
-Finish up. -Right!
-你收尾 -是
Bad doctors are better off dead.
醫術不好的醫生還不如死一死算了
You can add that to your paper.
你可以把這一句補在論文裡
I thought the move to Teika would help you mature a little.
我以為轉來帝華之後，你會成熟一點
-You're the same as always. -If there's a patient, I help them.
-結果跟以前沒兩樣呢 -有患者需要幫忙，我就去幫
That's all.
就這樣而已
No matter where I go,
不管去哪裡
my job remains the same.
我的工作都一樣
This is not enough.
這還不夠吧
This is all I was able to gather
我目前的情況
in my current situation.
只能湊到這些
I'll leave it then.
好吧，那就算了
But instead,
不然這樣吧
give me that.
你用那個來抵
Excuse me.
打擾了
Once again,
我再次自我介紹
I will be acting as coordinator for the trial.
我是您這次試驗的協調員
-My name is Kinoshita. -I wanted to say…
-我叫木下 -之前的事情
thank you.
謝謝你
-I… -First,
-我… -首先
I would like to introduce and explain the details of the trial.
我先向您介紹這次試驗的細節吧
With Ms. Yamamoto's permission,
山本小姐同意後
the second clinical trial of the Caesar
凱撒的第二場臨床試驗
was finally decided.
終於決定了
Ms. Kinoshita…
木下小姐
Thank you for fixing the IV mistake.
上次注射點滴的失誤，謝謝你幫忙
Thank you so much.
真的謝謝你
So…
那個…
Why did you decide to be Ms. Yamamoto's trial coordinator?
你為什麼決定當山本小姐的協調員？
If there's a patient…
有患者需要幫忙
If there's a patient, I help them.
有患者需要幫忙，我就去幫
I help that person.
我就去幫
That's all…
就這樣而已
Even if my job has changed from nurse to coordinator,
就算我的工作從護理師變成協調員
my duties and obligations remain the same.
我的責任跟義務並沒有變
Dr. Tokai taught me that.
這是渡海醫生教我的
Dr. Tokai did?
渡海醫生？
I have to do my best work, no matter what.
我必須對我的工作盡全力付出
But…
但是
Even the thought of wanting to help
只憑著想救人的念頭
is not enough to solve one problem.
還是有一個解決不了的問題
People.
那就是人
People?
人？
For a patient, and even for the doctors helping them,
對患者而言，即使有醫生的幫助
the biggest enemy is not sickness or disease.
最大的敵人不是疾病或病痛
A person's worst enemy…
人最大的敵人
is other people.
是人
A person's greatest enemy is other people.
人最大的敵人是人
Ms. Yamamoto said the same thing.
山本小姐也說過一樣的話
Being in my low-level position,
我當時的職位很低
there was nothing I could do.
所以無能為力
She also said that she wishes to accept the trial
她還說她願意參與試驗
in hopes that future patients can be helped as well.
是為了替醫療的未來盡一份力
She wants to help other people, too.
她也希望能幫助其他人
Nekota.
貓田
I have a job for you.
有個工作要給你
The fateful day finally arrived.
命運般的一天終於到來
Kaori.
香織小姐
I would like to talk to you about something.
我有話想跟你說
The doctors are waiting for you.
醫生在等你了
Please hurry.
請快點進去吧
If you would like to talk…
你想說的
I'll see you after your operation.
我們手術之後再聊吧
I hope the surgery goes well.
希望手術順利
Thank you.
謝謝
We'll now use the Japan-made Darwin, Caesar,
現在開始使用國產的達爾文“凱撒”
to perform aortic valve replacement surgery.
進行大動脈瓣膜置換手術
-Understood.
-拜託了
-You're saying this is a simple operation? -That's right.
-你說這是簡單的手術？ -是的
It will require delicate work, of course.
不過當然還是需要精密的操作
They'll have to suture the aorta.
他們必須縫合大動脈
It should be simple using the Caesar.
用凱撒應該很簡單
We can sit back and relax.
我們可以放心觀看了吧
Blockage complete.
阻斷完成
-I'll cut into the aorta. -Okay.
-切開大動脈 -是
The arms are moving much smoother than before.
機械手臂的動作比之前順暢很多
The improvements were a success.
改良得很成功
This suturing was always troublesome,
一向棘手的縫合步驟
but it's made to look so simple.
竟然這麼簡單就完成了
Complete.
完成
Removing forceps.
移除止血鉗
What's her condition?
情況如何？
-Stable. -Great.
-穩定 -太好了
Well done! A great success.
做得好，非常成功！
You all finish up.
交給你們收尾
-Good job. -Great work.
-辛苦了
Please wait!
請等一下
Direct the ultrasound to the left atrial appendage.
將超音波轉向左心耳的方向
Okay.
是
-That's… -A blood clot is loose!
-那是… -游離的血栓
BLOOD CLOT
（血栓或血凝塊）
A blood clot?
血栓？
We didn't see it in the tests.
檢查時都沒有看到
Dr. Takashina! We must remove it now!
-高階醫生 -必須移除才行
Dr. Kurosaki! Close up the patient for now.
黑崎醫生，先將病患縫合
Our planned operation was a success.
預定的手術已經成功完成了
If you act brash and something happens…
如果做多餘的事引起什麼問題
it will all be for nothing!
就前功盡棄了
Do you understand me, Dr. Kurosaki?
你懂我的意思吧，黑崎醫生？
We'll close up.
先縫合
If we ignore this, her life will be on the line!
如果忽視血栓 患者可能會有生命危險
If we act now, we can make it!
現在處理還來得及！
It wasn't part of the plan. We must close her up!
那並不是預定的手術計畫 我們必須先縫合
That is what hospital logic would say!
這是我們醫院的藉口
But to a patient, it's betrayal!
但是對患者而言，這是背叛
I will operate.
我來處理
-Help me. -Okay.
-幫我一下 -好
-Dr. Sera, support me. -Right!
-世良，你來協助我 -是
We'll now extract the left atrial appendage thrombus.
現在要取出左心耳的血栓
-Forceps, please. -Right.
-給我手術鉗 -是
Dr. Kurosaki!
黑崎醫生
I'm the head surgeon here. Don't touch her!
我是主刀醫生，別碰她
The thrombus doesn't matter right now.
血栓這種東西現在根本不要緊
That's right, Dr. Kurosaki!
是啊，黑崎醫生
You won't mind if I share this conversation with the patient?
不會介意我將你們現在的對話 轉告給病患知道吧？
What are you saying?
你在說什麼？
The rules are meant to be changed.
規則是用來改變的
We can't put a life on the line just because of some petty rules!
不能為了循規蹈矩 將患者的性命置於險地
Do what you want.
隨便你吧
-Opening the left atrium. -Right!
-打開左心房 -是
-Remove blood with the pump. -Right.
-用幫浦排血
Get 4-0 ready.
準備4-0號線
-Spoon too.
-是 -還有手術匙
Okay.
好的
Here.
麻煩了
-Get me the ultrasound. -What?
-給我超音波影像 -什麼？
I'll do it. Please.
-我來吧 -拜託了
Can he do it?
他可以嗎？
-Take out the thrombus. -Right.
-移除血栓 -好的
Extraction complete.
移除完成
Are you sure that's it?
沒有殘餘的血栓了吧？
Yes. That's it.
是，就只有這樣
Thank goodness.
謝天謝地
They managed to succeed without any incident.
他們成功完成，沒發生問題
It's all good since it worked out in the end.
幸好最後沒出什麼事
But how dare you use the intercom like that?
但你怎麼能擅自用對講機？
Forgive me.
很抱歉
Miyamoto, I'll finish up.
宮元小姐，我來收尾就好
Nekota.
貓田小姐
I'm already finished cleaning.
我們已經清理完了
There's one more thing we need to clean up.
還有一件事情需要理清楚
Well, we did stray from the original plan,
雖然發生了出乎意料的事情
but the operation was a success.
但是手術很成功
Mr. Tomizawa from the Ministry of Health will be pleased.
厚勞省的富澤先生會很高興的
We'll move on to the next trial at once.
快點進行下一次的試驗吧
-I'll leave it to you. -As for the next trial…
-那就拜託您了 -至於下次試驗…
-Dr. Tokai? -What are you doing here?
-渡海醫生？ -你有什麼事嗎？
-Go back to Teika University. -It was at Teika, actually…
-回去帝華大學 -我就是在帝華大學…
that I found these.
發現了這個
This is a list of our patients.
這是我們的患者名單
So it was leaked to Teika?
果然洩漏給帝華大學了嗎？
It wasn't me!
不是我做的！
-It couldn't be anyone else! -Unfortunately,
-不可能是別人 -真可惜
it was not Dr. Takashina here.
這件事不是高階醫生做的
The ID of the person who accessed the documents from Tojo's computer
登入東城大學電腦 查看這些資料的帳號
is written there on the document.
就寫在那份文件上面
The person who copied and stole the data
也就是說，複製並竊取資訊的
is that person.
就是那個人
Whose ID is this?
這是誰的帳號？
Excuse us.
打擾了
We looked up the owner of the ID number on the documents.
在渡海醫生的指示下 我找到了這個帳號的所有人
0019292.
0019292
0019293.
0019293
0019294.
0019294
Ayumi Miyamoto.
宮元亞由美
It's her ID number.
這是她的帳號
What have you done?
你做了什麼？
You were connected to Teika?
你跟帝華大學串通嗎？
What did they pay you?
他們給你多少錢？
Do you understand what you've done?
你知道你做了什麼嗎？
You've put us in quite a predicament!
你為我們造成很大的困擾
Can you tell us… what really happened?
說說看，到底發生了什麼事？
I've seen that terrified face.
像你那樣嚇壞的表情
I saw it once before.
我曾經看到過
She mistakenly handed the doctor the wrong tool.
木下小姐遞器具給醫生時拿錯了
Can you tell me what happened?
能告訴我發生了什麼事嗎？
It's okay.
沒事的
I will protect you.
我會保護你
I promise I will.
我跟你保證
Your dad has lung cancer, I hear.
我聽說你父親得肺癌
He's currently admitted to Tojo, too.
目前在東城這裡住院
In the executive suite.
還是住在特別病房
You can't afford that with your meager salary.
你那一點薪水付不起的
Who put you on this? Huh?
是誰幫你做了特殊安排的？
As an exchange,
作為交換
you were forced to copy the data.
你被迫複製資料
What did you say?
你說什麼？
Who was it?
是誰？
Tell me.
說
No crying.
不要哭
Hey.
喂
Say it.
快說
Who was it?
到底是誰？
I see you're teaching them well,
你把他們教得很好嘛
Director Moriya.
守屋院長
Director?
院長？
What? Nonsense.
什麼？胡說八道
I don't know about this.
我什麼都不知道
She stole the data herself!
是她自己竊取資料的
After all that, putting the blame on me?
你竟然還想栽贓我？
You're still running away after all this time?
都這樣了，你還想逃避嗎？
You're like a surgeon who has abandoned an operation.
簡直就像手術到一半放棄的醫生
What a pitiful hospital director you are.
而且你還是院長，丟不丟臉啊？
Lower than me. The lowest of low.
還不如我這種小醫生
Where's your proof that I have a hand in this?
你有什麼證據證明是我？
Get a grip, old man.
夠了吧，老頭子
SENT BY NOBUAKI MORIYA
（寄件人：守屋信明）
This is the email you sent to Teika.
這是你寄給帝華大學的郵件
The patient data was attached to the message.
這封信還夾帶了患者的資訊
There is a nice guy at Teika.
帝華大學有個好人
He was kind enough to lend me his ID card.
好心把他的證件借給我
When I logged in…
我登入電腦之後
DR. NISHIZAKI, I'VE ATTACHED A LIST OF ALL OUR PATIENTS.
（西崎醫生，承蒙關照 在此附上本院患者名單）
TOJO UNIVERSITY HOSPITAL DIRECTOR NOBUAKI MORIYA
（東城大學附屬醫院 院長 守屋信明）
…I found your email.
找到了你寄去的郵件
Director Moriya.
守屋院長
There's a rumor going around
聽說你退休之後
that Teika has a special position ready for you after you retire.
帝華幫你安排了特別的職位
Leaking patient data to a third party for your own lousy gain.
為了自己的利益，洩漏患者資料
This is a serious crime.
這可是非同小可的罪
I doubt that offer will still stand after this comes out.
要是傳出去 你那個職位應該也沒了吧
Please wait, Dr. Saeki!
等一下，佐伯醫生
I'll do anything! Please don't have me dismissed!
我什麼都願意做，只要別解雇我就好
In that case, I'll let it pass on one condition.
這樣的話，要我不追究只有一個條件
Anything at all!
什麼都可以
You will accept the return of Dr. Tokai from Teika University.
接受從帝華大學回來的渡海
You're getting bored over there, I'm sure.
你在那邊應該也覺得無聊了吧
You'll double his pay. Out of your own pocket.
薪水雙倍，掏你自己的腰包付
Okay.
好
Dr. Tokai.
渡海醫生
Um… Thank you so much.
那個…非常謝謝你
So you'll be coming back to Tojo?
您會回來東城大學嗎？
-There's something I need to do. -What?
-我在這裡還有事情要做 -什麼？
Huh? Dr. Tokai. You're back?
什麼？渡海醫生，你回來了？
Yes.
對
You know what that means, Dr. Sera.
世良，你知道這代表什麼意思
I'm…
我…
so sorry.
很抱歉
A person's greatest enemy is other people.
人最大的敵人是人
But…
但是
A person's best allies are people, too.
人最大的盟友也是人
What?
什麼？
When I was fired from being a nurse, it really was painful.
我被開除時，真的很痛苦
But…
但是
I was able to find a new job that I love.
我因此找到了我熱愛的工作
I took a different path, but my goals remain the same.
我走上不同的路，但我的目標不變
We're in this together.
我們是戰友
Very well.
好吧
I was planning on cutting Moriya off eventually anyway.
我本來就打算拋棄守屋
Why didn't you contact me?
您為什麼沒有聯絡我？
With this, Tojo won't be suspicious of you anymore, will they?
你這樣就不會 被東城大學的人懷疑了，不是嗎？
Accelerate the trials and get me that paper.
加快試驗腳步，完成論文
Right.
好的
There is a possibility that Dr. Saeki
不過，跟醫狙當時一樣
will stop the publication as he did with the Snipe paper.
或許佐伯教授這次也會阻止論文發表
Don't worry. Measures are in place.
別擔心，我做好對策了
There's nothing Dr. Saeki can do about it.
佐伯什麼都做不了的
Come in.
請進
Excuse me.
打擾了
If what you said the other day is true,
如果你前幾天說的屬實
Dr. Saeki has significant issues as a researcher.
那身為研究者的佐伯醫生 有很大的問題
I would like to ask his true intent.
我想把情況弄清楚
Yes. Go right ahead.
好，麻煩你查清楚
All done!
好了！
After we cleaned all this up, we had to put it back…
終於清理完，結果又要搬回來
What a struggle.
真是辛苦
He thinks about nothing but money.
他眼裡真的就只有錢
Do you think so?
是嗎？
Dr. Tokai said
渡海醫生說
he has something he needs to do at Tojo.
他在東城大學還有事情要做
Something he needs to do?
還有事情要做？
Forceps.
手術鉗？
I…
我…
I found a strange photo here recently.
前陣子在這裡看到了一張奇怪的片子
A photo?
片子？
An X-ray.
X光片
Inside the heart…
心臟那裡
there was a pair of forceps.
插了一把手術鉗
What?
什麼？
Why did Dr. Tokai have a photo like that?
渡海醫生怎麼有那樣的片子？
The final operation before the election.
理事長選舉前最後的手術
What's their name? Tell me!
他叫什麼名字？告訴我！
I have to take down Dr. Seigo Saeki.
我必須扳倒佐伯清剛
Dr. Nishizaki is operating at last.
西崎教授終於要親自動手術了
Perhaps Dr. Tokai is hoping for my failure.
或許渡海醫生希望我會失敗
We can't find Dr. Saeki anywhere.
我們到處都找不到佐伯醫生
Find out where he's going. Follow him.
找出他去哪裡，跟蹤他
There's a patient that Tojo doesn't want anyone to know about.
東城大學有一個 不想讓任何人知道的病患
In the end, it's people.
最終都還是要靠人
Man always prevails.
獲勝的，一定是人
Dr. Saeki!
佐伯教授！
It finally happened?
終於發生了？
Subtitle translation by:
字幕翻譯：林婉婷